

#### Profile

Experienced Software Engineer with 8 years of experience designing, developing, and deploying robust code for high-volume businesses in a highly collaborative, agile, and fast-paced environment. Possesses excellent communication skills, bringing forth extensive experience in performing research on product development processes and offering solutions and alterations to improve performance and scalability. I always have the pleasure to acquire valuable knowledge, diversified skills, strong leadership, and managerial capabilities to complement.

# **Employment History**

#### CEO at Swat Consulting, Swat, KP, Pakistan

August 2020 — Present

- Providing Software Development services as a registered company in Pakistan.
- Swat Consulting has delivered excellent software products.
- Managed software projects from the inception of the idea, to requirements, design, coding, testing, and disseminating.
- We have worked with local and international partners in different industries.
- Effectively multi-tasked and prioritized projects according to need.
- Effectively managed projects from start to finish.
- Technologies: Html, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Vue, Angular, Node, Python (Django, Flask), PHP (Laravel, Symfony), Jest, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, GitHub, GitLab, JIRA, Trello, Slack, Postman, Swagger, CI/CD, Circle CI.

## Product Engineer at Vidy, New York City

August 2020 — Present

Working as a Product Engineer at Vidy.

- Responsible for the design and creation of products.
- Duties include performing constant market analysis of competing products to determine and establish customer needs and requirements.
- **Technologies**: JavaScript, React JS, Svelte, Node JS, TypeScript, Elastic Search, SCSS, JSX, CSS Modules, GitHub, Slack.

#### Front End Engineer at NetGuru, Poznań, Poland

July 2020 — Present

- Working for a top software consulting company in Poland called NetGuru.
- Working as a Front End Engineer, for different companies based in US, UK, and Canada.

#### Details

Swat, KP, Pakistan, +923471920264

nadeem.ahmad.na@outlook.com

Date of birth 29/06/1995

Nationality Pakistan

Links

LinkedIn

Stackoverflow

GitHub

GitLab

Hackerrank

Portfolio

**Twitter** 

Google

Upwork

Behance

#### **Skills**

HTML5 / CSS3 / SCSS / Webflow

Styled Components / JSS / Radium / CSS Modules

React JS / Redux / Hooks / GraphQL

Angular 2+ / NgRx / RxJS

Vue / VueX / NuxtJS

JavaScript / ES6+ / JQuery

TypeScript / OOP

Three JS / Babylone / WebGL

Ember / Backbone / Meteor / Polymer

Node JS / Express / Next JS

Python / Django / Flask

PHP / Laravel / CodeIgniter

Svelte / State Management

MySQL / PostgreSQL / MariaDB

 Technologies: CSS, SCSS, CSS Modules, JavaScript, React JS, JSX, Redux, GitHub, GitLab, JIRA, Confluence, Postman, Slack, CI/CD, Code Reviewing, Pair Programming.

## Full Stack Software Engineer at IBM, Abu Dhabi

November 2019 — March 2020

- Started working as a Full-Stack Lead Engineer on TAMM project.
   TAMM's portal provides its customers, whether UAE citizens, residents, visitors or investors with a comprehensive range of government services through one single point of access at any time and place.
   Using TAMM's portal, customers can have direct access to information without having to visit each and every government entity.
- Technologies: React, Redux, Node, Express, TypeScript, Elastic Search, SonarQube, Jest, Docker, Gitlab, Gitlab Pipelines, Jira, Confluence, Microservice Architecture, Swagger, Postman, Slack.

## Full Stack Software Engineer at Eziline, Islamabad

2018 - 2019

- Worked as a Full Stack Developer on a Self-Serviced bus ticketing
  system into your website and let your visitors book bus tickets online.
  The online bus ticket reservation system is equipped with a powerful
  set of features allowing you to manage bookings, client data, create
  reports and translate the booking system without touching a line of
  code.
- Remained committed to learning and growing inside this exciting industry. Served as a facilitator for problem-solving and peaceful resolutions.
- Technologies: EcmaScript, TypeScript, Angular, Ngrx, Node, Express, MySQL, Swagger, Postgres, Docker, Kubernetes, GitHub, JIRA, Confluence, Slack, SonarQube, ElasticSearch, Azure DevOps, Postman, Swagger.

#### Front End Engineer at Maxtech, Swat, KP

2016 - 2018

- Lead a team to transform the aging application from classic asp to single page modern app. Developed single page application architecture of the new application with React JS & Web APIs. Gave hands-on training to engineers on SPA, React & JavaScript. Developed notifications, Ajax calls, drag & drop components.
- Worked to represent the company in a positive and enthusiastic manner. Managed a variety of internal communications.
- **Technologies**: React JS, JavaScript, Node and Express, PostgreSQL, GA, Swagger, PostMan, Slack.

# Full Stack Software Engineer at Teknords, Swat, KP, Pakistan 2012 – 2016

 Initially joined Teknords, worked for two years as an internee and then started working as a Full Stack Developer. Worked closely with business analysts, managed and trained small team of engineers.
 Project planning on lower level, tasks assignments, code testing and reviewing were the key roles I was involved in. MongoDB / CouchBase / DynamoDB

Redis / Memcached

Jest / Mocha / Enzyme / Karma

Machine Learning / Scikit-learn / Pytorch / Numpy

Microservices Architecture / RabbitMQ / Apache Kafka

Azure / AWS / GoogleCloud

Docker / Kubernetes / Jenkins

Azure DevOps / CI-CD / Ansible

Elasticsearch / Kibana / Logstash

WebPack / Gulp / Grunt

GitLab / GitHub / BitBucket

Agile Development / SCRUM

PostMan / Swagger

JIRA / Trello / Confluence

AJAX / JSON / REST / SOAP

OAuth / JWT / OpenID

Unit / Integration / E2E Testing

Casper JS / Puppeteer / Selenium

Linux / Mac / Windows

Debugging

**Active Listening** 

Adaptability

Communication

Creativity and Problem Solving

Critical Thinking

**Decision Making** 

Interpersonal Communication

Leadership and Management

**Public Speaking** 

Initiative and Problem-solving

Collaboration & Teamwork

- Worked to build long-term relationships with company stakeholders.
- Remained committed to learning and growing inside this exciting industry.
- Worked with a strong attention to detail and a keen eye for projects that need attention.
- **Technologies**: JavaScript, Jquery, PHP, Laravel, MySQL, Google Maps, Browser extensions, Web Scrapping, Slack, Swagger.

# Full Stack Software Engineer at Remote / Freelancing, Swat, KP, Pakistan

2013 - 2019

- Outsourced as a remote developer since 2016, worked for some bigger clients in Germany, United States of America, and, United Kingdom.
   I have developed Web Applications with real time capabilities over Firebase and Socket.IO, Browser Extensions, and Web Scrapping tools using Node JS, Puppeteer. I always had the enthusiasm to ensure the privacy of the information retrieved from the clients and to make the application secure validate the interactive inputs up to the ISMS standards
- Effectively participated in cross-team strategizing efforts to achieve optimal goals.
- Worked to represent the company in a positive and enthusiastic manner.

#### Education

## BS Software Engineering, University of Swat, Pakistan

2014 — 2018

- GPA 3.2 / 4.0
- Data Structures & Algorithms
- · Algorithm analysis
- Digital Logic & Designs
- Software Architecture & Designs
- Software Requirements & Specifications
- · Project Management
- Artificial Intelligence
- Cloud Computing
- · Cyber Security
- · Data Mining

#### Courses

Docker Essentials: A Developer Introduction, IBM - Cognitive Class

February 2020

#### Research Work

#### Big data and Deep Learning

January 2018 — September 2018

Successfully carried out research work in order to identify the challenges to Deep Learning in Big Data.

#### Languages

English

Urdu

**Pashto** 

#### **Hobbies**

Coding, Reading, Watching, Learning, Hiking, Photography

# Internships

## Internee at Teknords, Swat, KP, Pakistan

March 2012 — January 2014

- During my internship experience with Teknords, I was able to develop my Web Development Skills.
- I particularly found the Web Designing very interesting, and to be useful in improving my HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript Skills.
- I also learned Jquery and found it very useful to make a website interactive.
- Although I found JavaScript to be a little bit challenging when I dived deep into the data structures, I found it valuable in developing my algorithmic skills.

# **Y** Extra-curricular activities

#### AI & Machine Learning at Home

April 2019 — Present

- Sparing some time to learn and apply different machine learning techniques in our daily life routine.
- Have some good knowledge of Artificial Intelligence, Machine learning, and Deep Learning.
- Always follow and watch professionals the way they implement different AI algorithms.
- My top interests in the field of AI are Computer Vision and Robotics.